Resume

View the Project on GitHub at https://github.com/

Myles J. Johnson-Gray

mjayegray@gmail.com | 302-670-9580

Education

- University of Delaware (Aug 2015 May 2017)
 - Master of Science in Computer Science
 - GPA: 3.2
- Delaware State University (Aug 2011 May 2015)
 - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Magna Cum Laude
 - GPA: 3.5

Summary

Creative and adaptable software engineer (with 5+ years of experience) offering proficiency in scripting and object-oriented programming, as well as strong teamwork and communication skills. Seeking new opportunities to utilize my skills towards creating meaningful software.

Specific interests: Artificial Intelligence, UI/UX, music

Technical Skills

Languages/Frameworks

C++, Java, Python, HTML/CSS/Javascript, NodeJS, SQL, VBScript, .NET

Mathematics

Calculus, probability, statistics, trigonometry, discrete mathematics, linear algebra, theory of computation

Systems/Software

Wireshark, VirtualBox, Docker, Eclipse, Visual Studio, GitHub, Rational Clearcase, Jira, Jenkins, Confluence, Froglogic Squish, Office 365/SharePoint/Power Automate, SmartBear Collaborator

Relevant Experience

RTX Corporation - Software Engineer II

Tewksbury, Massachusetts, USA

- Secret Clearance from U.S. Department of Defense
- Six Sigma Specialist Green Belt certification

Patriot Tools Team (Dec 2020 - Present)

- Developing VBA scripts, processes, and documentation for maintaining company financial data using Office 365, Microsoft Share Point, and Power Automate.
- Producing in-house scripting and front-end tools (Python, .NET, PHP, Perl, VBScript) to improve development and testing efficiency of engineering teams.
- Responsible for introducing DevSecOps, CI/CD, and Agile tools (Jira, Jenkins, Collaborator, GitHub) and concepts to outdated engineering product groups.
- Maintaining and developing enhancements for a classic ASP.NET scheduler tool to support classified lab testing functions.
- Coordinating with stakeholders to develop requirements, receive feedback, and address urgent issues or bugs with Tools products.
- Completing training courses supporting Agile frameworks, methodologies, and practices within the Patriot Tools team.

Patriot Maintenance & Diag Team (May 2018 - Dec 2020)

- Implemented and facilitated the delivery of maintenance/diagnostic software (Ada/C++) for the Patriot system.
- Performed integration and regression testing with classified hardware for scheduled releases.
- Produced, revised, and ran test plans for Patriot system maintenance procedures in classified lab environments.
- Developed automated GUI and unit testing for maintenance software, using Froglogic Squish (Python) to replace manual regression tests.

Delaware State University - Undergraduate Researcher

Dover, Delaware, USA (Feb 2012 - May 2015)

- Assisted in the software development of NeRvolver, a computational intelligence-based system (using evolutionary algorithms and fuzzy logic) for automated construction, analysis, and tuning of neuronal models.
- Implemented NSGA-2 and END_VEGA evolutionary algorithms in C++, and performed an empirical algorithm analysis applied to neuronal modeling.
- Implemented statistical functions for analysis of neuronal data (SPSS).
- Prepared oral and poster presentations for national and international symposiums and conferences.

Summer Research Internships

Clemson University, South Carolina, USA (May 2014 - July 2014)

- Participated in a number of courses covering SSH, operating systems, and object-oriented programming fundamentals.
- Developed a graph ontology based system for keyword extraction of biomedical publications (Java).
- Prepared an oral and poster presentation for a local symposium.

Ningbo University, Ningbo, China (May 2012 - July 2012)

National Institute of Health sponsored internship opportunity.

- Participated in courses covering knowledge of various data mining techniques, including clustering, classification methods, and decision trees.
- Utilized knowledge from courses to develop and compare information gain based decision trees (Python), to predict NBA player shot selections and results based on a number of in-game critieria.

Github Repositories

Each bullet below contains a hyperlink mapping to the respective repository location.

- Constructed a character prediction system using bigrams to generate predictions for a dynamic AAC keyboard.
- Implemented shading, reflection/refraction, bump mapping, model loading, and flocking schemas in graphics projects using OpenGL.
- Created a Perl program to simulate the mutation and alignment of amino acid sequences using a PAM matrix.
- Built and tested a decision tree class on breast cancer data obtained from University of Wisconsin Hospitals in Madison, WI.
- Developed a Forward Chaining Knowledge Base of restaurants for Main Street (Newark, Delaware).
- Designed a stock market QA system using sentiment analysis.
- Produced a system that uses Hidden Markov Models through viter bitraining to find the most likely path for given genome sequences.

AUTHORED PUBLICATIONS

- "Hybridization of multi-objective evolutionary algorithms and fuzzy control for automated construction, tuning, and analysis of neuronal models" peer-reviewed abstract, Patel P., Johnson-Gray M., Forren E., Malik A., and Smolinski T.G., BMC Neuroscience 14(Suppl 1):P369, 2013.
- "NeRvolver: a computational intelligence-based system for automated construction, tuning, and analysis of neuronal models" peer-reviewed abstract, Forren E., Johnson-Gray M., Patel P., and Smolinski T.G., BMC Neuroscience 13(Suppl 1):P36, 2012.

SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

- Computational Neuroscience (CNS) Conference (Atlanta 2012, Paris 2013)
- Annual Biomedical Research Conference for Minority Students (ABRCMS) (San Jose 2012, Nashville 2013, San Antonio 2014)
- Emerging Researchers National (ERN) Conference (Washington D.C 2014)

Project maintained by **gitmyles**Hosted on GitHub Pages — Theme by **orderedlist**